Contact

7022049122 (Home) matthewleiman@aol.com

www.linkedin.com/in/matthew-leiman-7404a0158 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Knowledge Management Project Management Critical Thinking

Certifications

Google Analytics Certification
Digital Sales Certification
Google Ads Mobile Certification
Google Ads Search Certification
Google Ads Display Certification

Matthew Leiman

Computer Software Engineering Student at Emerging Digital Academy

Fargo

Summary

I have worked in the Mobile Application/Gaming and Digital Marketing fields for 6 years, gaining a lot of experience in not only how the back-end of how online MMO's work, but management, leadership and recruiting, while accumulating a love for helping individuals succeed in their positions and making an impact on others.

The efficiency that I have, along with the time that I am able to complete a project in, is something that I take great pride in. My passion for creativity, efficiency, and organization, is something that has always been natural to me since I started working, but this doesn't just apply to my career.

I am focused on putting my passions and skills to good use by supporting organizations and projects that I really care about.

Outside of the office I exemplify this on the ice (I play hockey, its one of my favorite things to do), at school, in my music, and at home.

Thank you for taking the time to read this and if you believe I am a good fit for your company, don't hesitate to reach out! I look forward to hearing from you soon.

Experience

Emerging Digital Academy
Computer Software Engineering Student
Page 1 of 6

July 2020 - Present (5 months)

Fargo, North Dakota, United States

- Full Stack Development
- Javascript, jQuery, C#, Dotnet, React, Redux
- Html, CSS, Bootstrap, Material-UI, API systems
- Git, SQL, Postgres, Express, Nodejs

Revenue Media Group Digital Marketing Manager April 2019 - August 2020 (1 year 5 months)

Las Vegas, Nevada Area

- Improved web presence through SEO, A/B Testing, successfully increasing overall website traffic
- Utilized Google Analytics & Google Tag Manager to gather and track website metrics as well as install the necessary Tags.
- -Drove initiatives such as marketing performance reports, developed new scoring techniques, and increase KPI's
- Built UTM codes to track which avenue digital ads were being directed from.
- Built and set up digital campaigns in Google ads, Facebook, Bing, & Linkedin
- Created, directed, & Managed campaigns from across all types of businesses. From Casinos to Orthodontists.
- Managed social media strategy across channels
- Created A/B testing campaigns. Analyzed data to improve messaging and increase user return rate & decrease bounce rate
- Used Ninja cat to organize Marketing Reports, Dashboards, & Data Pipelines
- Utilized the Call Rail service to record and tie phone calls to specific ads to quality assure and record additional metrics.
- Boosted conversion rates and revenue by developing & implementing new content strategy.
- Constantly stayed up to date with new products, content, and strategies to maximize performance and profits.

Easy Street Realty
Marketing Manager/Administrative Assistant
December 2018 - May 2019 (6 months)
Las Vegas

-In charge of all Social Media & Marketing Campaigns

- -Administrative Assistant to one of the top 150 Real Estate Agents in Las Vegas -Primary usage of Photoshop to create marketing guides, brochures, templates, as well as editing photos for mass production and every day use.
- -Appointment setting, appointment check ups and follow ups. -Heavy utilization of Facebook, Instagram, & Twitter ad campaigns.
- -Conducted interviews for other employee recruits. -Updated branch website blogs and used Search Engine optimization to increase website traffic.
- -In charge of all IT work in office.
- Utilized Mailchimp to send out mass marketing emails
- -Set up computers, networks, and network devices with continuous maintenance.
- -Everyday use of Real Estate databases for lead generation and tracking.
- -Mass printing and distribution of all original works (brochures, postcards, flyers) from Xerox. -Retaining everyday knowledge of how the real estate industry works and how to prosper in it.

ΜZ

Game Ambassador/Knowledge Management Specialist December 2015 - October 2018 (2 years 11 months) Las Vegas, Nevada Area

- -Responsible for a back-end knowledge base that provides a universal encyclopedia for all employees and stakeholders working on Final Fantasy XV: A New Empire, Game of War, and Mobile Strike, as well as point of contact for all floor agents, Vendors, and management.
- -Performed initial client assessment and analysis to begin research process.
- -Created boardroom multimedia presentations that are video and text synced for enhanced understanding.
- -Liaison between Live Operations departments, Design Departments, Quality Assurance, and customer service.
- -Conducted weekly inventory of hundreds of items including software, hardware, and accessories. -Proficiency in using JIRA, Confluence, and Zendesk.
- -Handling tickets with JIRA, routing incidents to correct departments.
- -Active directory administration of groups, users and workstations -Managed and implemented item management, provisioning, order processing, asset scheduling, and inventory control
- -Asset management and accountability in Daily routines of ordering, tracking, and receiving supplies. -Worked with other departments to resolve issues. (engineering, application support, tech services, facilities, etc)

- -Installed and configured proprietary software.
- Direct target marketing for premium players
- -Achieved accolades as well as bonuses and raises based on performance.
- -Excelled in a self managed work environment.
- -Used Microsoft Office and Google Sheets/Docs to record work data.
- -Handled outages of different systems through email and JIRA notifications and alerting the on call employee dealing with the affected system.
- -Providing leadership, direction and information with utmost proficiency and accuracy.
- Used Abobe Photoshop to make detailed graphics and imagery pertaining to training achievements and company clothing

TELUS International

Senior Subject Matter Expert

December 2014 - December 2015 (1 year 1 month)

Las Vegas, Nevada Area

- -Served as a subject matter expert (SME) for both the Google Wallet and Google Play campaigns. -Communicated directly with Google on a daily basis to up-train on new updates, features, and functionalities of both the Google Wallet and Google Play applications.
- -Relayed all new information to peers via presentation in a classroom setting using Microsoft tools. -Troubleshooting software problems on Windows and Macintosh operating systems. -Troubleshooting software issues with Windows and Mac iOS, as well as many others related to the environment.
- -Trained peers on providing an accurate, trustworthy, and stellar customer service experience.
- -Used Microsoft Office and Google Sheets/Docs to record work data.
- -Working with other departments to resolve issues. (engineering, application support, tech services, facilities, etc)
- Axis for customer inquiries regarding reports, asset availability, research, support and redistribution orders.
- -Troubleshooting hardware of Laser, thermal and receipt printers, Point of sale terminals, desktops and laptops.
- -Responsible for personal user information
- -Excelled in a very team based, friendly, and competitive environment.
- -Conducted full interviews and hiring reports for recruitment

Clark County

Election Machine Programmer/Information Technology July 2014 - November 2014 (5 months)

Las Vegas, Nevada Area

- -Temporary job with the Clark County Elections Department.
- -Responsible for the programming and delivery of county voting machine during early voting time. -Conducted work in a warehouse setting.
- Ensured that timely delivery of machines and machine supplies returned for repair/modification were processed for transport to warehouse.
- Logistics support and full accountability coordinating with warehouse staff regarding relocation and transportation arrangements of voting machines.
- -Prepared documentation and coordinated transportation of resources
- -Reclaimed old network and voting devices from public voting sites for disposal or repair.
- -Marked and labeled all cargo; documented, verified, and inventoried cargo; prepared and submitted report documentation.

Maintained accurate records and managed warehouse correspondence.

Created using Resumonk - Online Resume Builder

- -Excelled at coordinating tasks of numerous internal divisions to ensure rapid, accurate delivery of equipment, materials, and resources.
- -One of three leads in charge of a 25 + man team.
- -Responsible for repair, internally and externally of voting machines.
- -Deployment, configuration and setup of desktops and laptops
- -Configured workstations network criteria
- -Directed on-site management and maintenance of voting machines
- -Installed and configured proprietary software.
- -Logistics
- -Active directory administration of groups, users and workstations
- -Participated in the administration of municipal elections, such as preparation or distribution of ballots, appointment or training of election officers, and tabulation or certification of results.
- -Planned and directed the maintenance, filing, safekeeping, and computerization of all municipal documents.

Smith's Food & Drug Centers Assistant Produce Manager August 2010 - November 2013 (3 years 4 months)

Las Vegas, Nevada Area

- -Assistant Produce Manager to the highest grossing Produce Department in the Las Vegas Area. -Assistant Head of an 8 man team dedicated to providing the best customer service possible.
- -Ensured expense control within operating budget.

- -Axis for customer inquiries regarding reports, asset availability, research, support and redistribution orders.
- -Track record of identifying redundancies and maximizing resources to streamline operations. Proficient in a variety of logistics and supply management software, both proprietary and commercial. Used spreadsheets and Microsoft excel to submit orders of produce from distributors of product. Excelled at coordinating tasks of numerous internal divisions to ensure rapid, accurate delivery of equipment, materials, and resources.
- -Led by example of providing the highest rated customer service score out of all Smith's Food and drug Stores.
- -Filled department with fresh fruits and vegetables, some of which required to be cleaned and prepared before hand.
- -Interviewed and hire staff, and oversee staff training.
- -Conducted quarterly cycle counts of inventory materials and product based on computer monitored and suggested re ordering and intuition
- -Managed and implemented item management, provisioning, order processing, asset scheduling, and inventory control
- -Control purchasing department budgets.

Education

University of Nevada-Las Vegas Computer Science · (2015 - 2019)

College of Southern Nevada

Associate of Science - AS, Computer Science · (2013 - 2015)